# Jonathan Fisher

LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/jonathanfisher2 • jgf0200@gmail.com • (949) 232-9045

# **SUMMARY**

I am a results-driven risk/data analyst with a passion for all things data and a love for education. With my combined experience in driving revenue for a Fortune 500 retail company and writing/reporting for Business Insider, I am confident that I can merge my communication and analytical skills to provide immediate value to SparkPost as a Jr. Compliance Analyst.

#### **EDUCATION**

## University of California, Berkeley

**B.A. Political Economy** 

## **Certifications/Training and Development:**

- Digital Analytics: Google Analytics Individual Qualification (Received April 2018)
- Databases: Stanford University Certificate of Achievement in Database Management: SQL (Received April 2018)
- Databases: Oracle Database for Developers Certificate of Completion (Received April 2018)
- Information Technology: Google IT Support Professional Certificate (Expected: June 2018)

#### **SKILLS**

- **Technical**: Microsoft (Excel, Outlook, PPT, Word), G-Suite, Aspect Elite LP, Sugar CRM, SQL, MySQL, Google Analytics, Tableau, Adobe Photoshop, Comfortable in Linux/Unix shells, Basic Python scripting
- Language: Fluent in Japanese, Elementary proficient in Spanish

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Associate Investigative Risk and Fraud Analyst**

Oct. 2016 - Feb. 2018

Degree Attained: May 2016

Ross Stores, Inc. | Dublin, CA

- Recouped \$120,000+ in revenue from uncovering internal fraud/external theft; accounted for more than 20% of total company revenue recouped from internal fraud; liaised with third party vendors to resolve customer chargeback issues
- Uncovered 145+ cases of internal fraud by utilizing exception-based reporting and querying/extracting data using SQL
- Discovered and froze \$100,000+ in fraudulently bought gift cards using Aspect Elite LP, SQL, and Excel
- Led the development and technical training of 12+ new and current analysts on finding cases using various analytical tools; recognized by management as the lead investigator and internal fraud compliance analyst
- Responded to 15+ crisis incidents daily at 1,700+ stores; monitored all store locations to ensure the security of store employees and property
- Prepared and presented weekly written and statistical reports for company executives pertaining to risk, internal fraud, severe weather, and international travel; Nominated for Associate of the Month 6 times by peers and managers
- Primary point of contact for assessing and determining daily travel risks for corporate partners by utilizing media sources and intelligence reports

### **Vice President and Co-Founder**

Sept. 2015 - Oct. 2016

"Back from the Edge" Campaign | UC Berkeley, CA

- Developed and executed a campaign against violent extremism by creating an interactive video game targeting isolated youth and other at-risk individuals; downloaded by 100+ users
- Honorable mention (1 of 12 teams worldwide invited to present in D.C.) for a global case competition sponsored by Facebook and the Department of State seeking ways to use digital means to combat violent extremism

## **Editorial Reporter/Intern**

Feb. 2015 – Aug. 2015

Business Insider | San Francisco, CA

- · Pitched and wrote 2-3 articles a day for various verticals including tech, lifestyle, politics, foreign affairs, and sports
- Moderated daily content for 50,000+ people on the BI: Tech Facebook page and gained 300+ new followers
- Performed extensive research and wrote 35+ articles that reached 1,000 to 200,000+ viewers

## **Business Development Representative**

June 2014 - Jan. 2015

Sikka Software | Milpitas, CA

- Maintained excellent relationships with 5+ major partner accounts while growing sales targets by 10% in medical verticals
- Responsible for auditing and tracking partner billing accounts to resolve account discrepancies
- Promoted from intern to full-time associate within 3 months and maintained an unparalleled customer service record

#### Lab IT Assistant

Sept. 2013 - May 2014

Haas School of Business | Berkeley, CA

- Provided basic hardware and software troubleshooting for 400+ UC Berkeley MBA candidates and faculty members
- · Supervised and trained new lab assistants; video-recorded 20+ MBA classes to provide webcasts for students